# **James Chong**

Address: 1 Mei Tin Road, Tai Wai, N.T. Hong Kong Tel No.: +852 63852276 Email: longshanj@gmail.com

Developer with 4 years of experience delivering projects and programs to clients and colleagues. Driven self-starter and independent programmer who loves exploring and learning newest technologies. Proactive team-player with strong communication skills and with experience in management and administrative work.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## WORKING FAMILY AND STUDENT FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE AGENCY, HKSAR

**Hong Kong** 

December 2021 - Present

Analyst/Programmer II

- Defined requirements and workflows for a public facing services' forms and admin portal according to business users' requirements, which the service supported 10000+ citizens monthly with faster subsidy access
- Prepared and conducted system tests, including unit test, regression test and load test for public facing services. Developed numerous regression tests with Selenium and Katalon and introduced my department to automated testing, which increased the speed of completing sets of regression tests by around 50%
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams on multiple enhancement projects for public website and intranet function, which facilitated colleagues' daily operations and subsidy processes for the citizens

### **CATALYST SOLUTIONS LIMITED (Subsidiary of Dynasys Solutions Limited)**

**Hong Kong** 

Developer / IT consultant

October 2020 - October 2021

- Designed and/or developed RPA programs for different companies, including Hong Kong Electric Corporation Limited and Yazaki (Hong Kong) Limited, which automated hours-long operations with minimum human intervention
- Participated in SAP BW/BO installation and development for different companies, including Citistore (Hong Kong) Limited, Aviation Security Company Limited, etc

#### **EDUCATION**

#### CITY UNIVERSITY OF HONG KONG

**Hong Kong** 

Master of Science in Data Science

September 2022 – June 2024

First Class Honours with Distinction, Outstanding Research Project Award in Sem B 2022/23

#### THE HONG KONG POLYTECHNIC UNIVERSITY

Hong Kong

Bachelor of Science in Computing, Major: Computing; Minor: Applied Psychology Second Class Honours, Division 1 (Upper-second Class) September 2016 – June 2020

#### **SKILLS**

- Experienced in MySQL and Python, including data analytics related framework
- Proficient in UiPath (RPA software), Selenium and Katalon (Automated testing tools), Articulate Storyline and Canvas (Instructional Designer tool and Learning Management System)
- Fluent in Cantonese, English & Mandarin